James Weisman

Cary, IL 60013 jweisman08@gmail.com 8478286465

I am a creative, talented and motivated individual. I am a quick learner with the ability to work independently or on a team. I have experience in Desktop and Server Support and Systems Administration. I have been an IT Manager with Proven training ability and managing end-user and computer support technicians. I have most recently have been attending McHenry County College in Crystal Lake, studying Web Design & Development and have earned a certificate in web design, and now I am looking to get back into the technology. field. I have done freelance website support and design work while in school. working with both WordPress, Square Space, Wix, Joomla, MailChimp and most recently with Divi builder and duda. Other skills that I have acquired over the past two years has been designing and working with Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, GIMP, Inkscape, Figma Design, Axure RP 9, Woo Commerce web page (class project), working with the new Gutenberg WordPress Editor, dealing with web hosting companies for my clients. I have worked with Sass and LESS. Working with and improving the SEO for my client's web sites

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Inspector/Packer

Technipaq Inc. - Crystal Lake, IL April 2017 to Present

Factory worker. This is a temp job to get me through school and until I find another job where I can use my web design and technology skills.

Web Design Student

McHenry County College - Crystal Lake, IL June 2017 to 2019

I have most recently have been attending McHenry County College in Crystal Lake, studying Web Design & Development and have earned a certificate in web design, and now I am looking for work. I have done freelance website support and design work. working with both WordPress, Square Space, Joomla, and MailChimp. I have experience as a desktop and server Support, System Administration. I have been an IT Manager with Proven training ability and managing end user and computer support personal. Other skills that I have acquired has been designing a Woo Commerce web page (class project), working with the new Gutenberg WordPress Editor, dealing with web hosting companies for my clients. Learning and working with Sass and LESS. Working with and improving the SEO for my client's web sites

District Technical Support Specialist Tier 2

Glenbard High School District 87 - Carol Stream, IL 2014 to 2016

- Supported administrators, staff and students
- Used Solar-winds trouble ticket system

- Supported Windows7 and Apple computers
- Supported iPads and other mobile devices
- Supported Microsoft Office 2010 & 2016
- Experience with trouble shooting, imaging, fixing of hardware, software and network problems.
- Web & Social Media Master for the Athletic booster club.

Instructor

Kaneland Community Unit School District 302 - Maple Park, IL August 2013 to June 2014

Taught classes in PC Maintenance, repair, networking, Web Design and Development, HTML and Cascading Style Sheets

Part-Time Instructor

COMPUTER SYSTEMS INSTITUTE 2011 to 2014

Taught introduction to Computers, CompTIA A+ and CompTIA Net+ classes.

INSIGHT GLOBAL - Consultant

Baxter Health Care 2010 to 2011

as a computer consultant. I was a part of a team that migrated 500+ users to new computers at multiple locations across the country

Adjunct Professor/Web Master

COLLEGE OF LAKE COUNTY 2009 to 2010

Taught a class for one semester called PC Operating Systems for A+ Certification. I had the added responsibility of being the Web Master for Adjunct Professor website

Computer Teacher

LAKE COUNTY TECHNOLOGY CAMPUS 2007 to 2009

Taught classes that covered hardware and operating systems (Windows, Linux and MAC)

Technology Coordinator

FOX LAKE DISTRICT 2006 to 2007

- I was the District Technology Coordinator for District 115 in Fox Lake. I was responsible for the computers, servers and networks at two schools
- Improved the reliability of the District's backup and recovery system, proposed improvements to the school Norton Ghosting procedures, and improved security for the online storage of teacher and student data

Student

Illinois State University - Normal, IL 2003 to 2006

I went back to school to obtain a Certification in Technology Education, with an endorsement in Computer Applications

Manager/System Administrator

MOTOROLA INC

2000 to 2003

- I managed a staff of four Local Desktop Support Technicians
- I over saw the installation of a new network at a new off-site location
- I was in charge of the purchasing of computers
- Managed Microsoft & Unix Servers, printers, back-up systems, for two different divisions

Systems Administrator

Open Text - Bannockburn, IL 1998 to 2000

Enterprise Content Management company

Education

Web Design & Development

McHenry County College - Crystal Lake, IL December 2018

Certification in Technology Education

Illinois State University - Normal, IL

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Education and Technology in Industrial Education and Technology

Western Illinois University - Macomb, IL

Skills

- BUYING/PROCUREMENT (3 years)
- CompTIA (4 years)
- Linux (2 years)
- Unix (3 years)
- HTML (10+ years)
- CSS (2 years)
- Javascript (Less than 1 year)
- bootstrap (Less than 1 year)
- Adobe suites (Less than 1 year)
- Photoshop (Less than 1 year)
- Illustrator (Less than 1 year)
- Indesign (Less than 1 year)
- Dreamweaver (1 year)
- responsive design (Less than 1 year)
- · Lucid chat
- Git (Less than 1 year)
- Web Design
- Wireframe
- Wordpress (4 years)

- Website
- Google Analytics (1 year)
- Google Adwords (Less than 1 year)
- PHP (Less than 1 year)
- · Graphic Design
- Adobe
- HTML 5
- MySQL
- Python (Less than 1 year)
- Adobe Premiere Pro (Less than 1 year)
- Adobe After Effects (Less than 1 year)
- Server Management (10+ years)
- Sass (Syntactically Awesome Style Sheets) (Less than 1 year)
- Teaching Experience (5 years)
- Project Management (10+ years)
- Help Desk (10+ years)
- System Administration (10+ years)
- System Support (10+ years)
- Network Administration (10+ years)
- Customer Supp (10+ years)
- Training & Development (5 years)
- Web Servers (4 years)
- Support Manager (5 years)
- Solar-winds trouble ticket system (2 years)

Links

https://theweisman.wordpress.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-weisman-4002a316/

Additional Information

Information Technology Skills

- Web site design and management
- Windows (xp, 7,8,10), Apple OS & iOS, Unix/Linux desktop
- Microsoft (Active Directory), Microsoft web server, Unix/Linux DNS server, Apple servers
- Management of desktop support personal
- Purchasing of equipment and supplies
- Worked as part of a several management teams that built and setup new offices
- Telecommunication/Voicemail and Teleconferencing systems

Computer Certifications:

- CompTIA A+ and CompTIA Net+ 005
- Microsoft Technology Associate: Networking, Windows Operating Systems, Server Administration, Security
- Apple Certified Associate Mac Integration